Guide to the Morris Raphael Cohen Papers 1898-1981
University of Chicago Library
Cohen, Morris Raphael. Papers
1898-1981
36 linear feet (72 boxes)
Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Morris Raphael Cohen (1880-1947), Philosopher. Papers highlight Cohen's influence as an early proponent of legal philosophy; his career as a teacher of philosophy, especially at the City College of New York; Jewish concerns and his affiliation with the Conference on Jewish Relations; writings on the philosophy of history, the philosophy of science, social philosophy, logic and ethics; and an extensive correspondence with family, friends, professional associates, and major contemporary philosophers.
Information on Use
Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical Note
Morris Raphael Cohen was born in Minsk, Russia, in 1880. The son of Abraham Mordecai and Bessie Farfel Cohen, Morris came to the United States at the age of twelve. His family eventually settled in New York City. In 1895 Morris took the entrance examination for the City College of New York and scored the highest grade. While a student at CCNY Cohen met Thomas Davidson who strongly influenced Cohen's burgeoning liberalism. Davidson founded the progressive Breadwinners' College, where Cohen gained his initial teacher's training.
Morris married Mary Ryshpan in 1906. They had three children, Felix S., Leonora D., and Victor W.
Following Davidson's death in 1900, Cohen helped form the Thomas Davidson Society. Under the auspices of New York's Educational Alliance, the Society opened a night school. Among the supporters were William Harris, Charles Bakewell, Josiah Royce, and Percival Chubb. The public education system assumed control of the school in 1917.
Morris taught briefly in the New York public schools before becoming a mathematics instructor at CCNY. While teaching, Cohen took graduate courses at Columbia University. He left Columbia and CCNY to pursue his Ph.D. in philosophy at Harvard, which he received in 1906. He returned to New York and continued as mathematics instructor, despite his degree in philosophy, until 1912. After six years he transferred to the Philosophy Department. He stayed on at CCNY until 1938, enjoying stays as a visiting professor at Columbia, Yale, Yale Law School, Harvard, Stanford and elsewhere. To accommodate his wish to spend more time writing, Cohen took a position at the University of Chicago, where he carried a light, but influential, teaching load in the Philosophy Department, 1938-1941. Before his death in January, 1947, Cohen published numerous articles and books including Reason and Nature, 1931; Law and the Social Order, 1933; Preface to Logic, 1944; and Faith of a Liberal, 1945. Missing from the papers are drafts of his autobiography, A Dreamer's Journey.
Leonora Cohen Rosenfield, after collecting her father's extensive collection of papers, published in 1948 Morris' biography, Portrait of a Philosopher. Her research materials for the biography and correspondence with many of Morris' colleagues are also represented in the papers.
Scope Note
Series I: PERSONAL AND PROFESSIONAL CORRESPONDENCE, 1899-1946, comprises 6.5 linear feet of personal and professional correspondence, arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Much of Cohen's outgoing correspondence was recovered by his daughter Leonora Cohen Rosenfield (see also Series VI: Leonora Cohen Rosenfield Papers). The correspondence provides a detailed chronicle of Cohen's personal contacts, including the early exchange of letters between Morris and Mary Ryshpan. The correspondence also reflects Cohen's associations with philosophers such as William James, George Herbert Palmer, William T. Harris, William Sheldon, Josiah Royce, Felix Adler, Frederick Woodbridge, Percival Chubb, Hugo Münsterberg, and Ralph Barton Perry. Former students of Cohen's with whom he corresponded include Ernest Nagel, Herbert Scheider, Sidney Hook, Paul Weiss, Joseph Ratner, Phillip Weiner, and Isadore Silver.
Other correspondents include Bertrand Russell, W. A. Overstreet, Edmund Husserl, Albert O. Lovejoy, John Dewey, and David Swenson. The Overstreet letters describe much of the academic life at City College of New York. Only one letter exists in the collection from George Santayana, but it offers an appraisal of Cohen's book, Reason and Nature. Correspondence with Albert Einstein concerns comments on noted German scientists, as well as Einstein's opinions of Bertrand Russell and Cohen's work for the Conference on Jewish Relations.
Richard McKeon, James H. Tufts, Charner Perry, William F. Ogburn, Frank Knight, Louis Gottschalk, Alfred Kozybski, Rudolph Carnap and Robert Hutchins are among the University of Chicago faculty correspondents. Other correspondents during Cohen's tenure at Chicago include H. L. Mencken, Talcott Parsons, Edwin Arlington Robinson, Walter Lippman, Harold Laski, Theodore Roosevelt, Ambassador Fernando de los Rios, Douglas McArthur, Archibald MacLeish, and Reinhold Niebuhr.
Cohen believed that a philosophy curriculum should include courses in legal philosophy, and because of his interest in law he developed close relationships with important figures in the legal professions. Among those represented in the correspondence are Roscoe Pound of Harvard Law School, Judge Learned Hand, and Supreme Court Justices Oliver W. Holmes, Louis Brandeis, William O. Douglas, Benjamin Cardozo, and Felix Frankfurter.
Series II: WRITINGS BY COHEN AND STUDENTS' PAPERS, 1898-1938,
Cohen's manuscripts include holograph and typescript drafts. The drafts include both preliminary and later stages of The Meaning of Human History, American Thought, Faith of a Liberal, and A Preface to Logic. An edited typescript of Reason and Nature appears in this section, along with many smaller articles that were later incorporated into the book. Some unpublished drafts are "19th Century Thought"; "Will to Illusion"; and Cohen's PhD thesis from Harvard, "The Place of Happiness in the Kantian Philosophy." Series II also includes examples of Cohen's students' papers and examinations from the 1930s.
This series also includes notes on topics of philosophic inquiry, including history, law, logic, metaphysics, religion, philosophy of science, and psychology. Also included are his criticisms of ancient and modern philosophers including Descartes, Dewey, Rousseau, Spinoza, Whitehead, and Kant.
Series III: PERSONAL PAPERS, PAPERS RELATING TO THOMAS DAVIDSON, AND OTHER PAPERS, 1898-1980 consists of a variety of materials, both personal and professional. Includes correspondence, notes, Cohen's diaries, personal notebooks, and a draft of the [auto]biography of Morris Cohen, student examinations, reports, notes Cohen took as a student, his diplomas from CCNY and Harvard, a 1930 passport, and several appointment books, 1944-1947. Contains bank statements, class attendance records, family photographs, and other material. Newspaper clippings, articles about Morris Cohen (including some published after his death), conference programs are also included.
Less personal material relates to Thomas Davidson who taught Cohen Greek and Latin. Included are Davidson's lectures and notes on Socrates, Aeschylus, Aristotle, and Plato. Also included are lecture drafts and notes pertaining to the Breadwinners' College, a continuing education program initiated by Davidson, and material from the Thomas Davidson Society, which ran a similar educational program after Davidson's death under the Educational Alliance.
Papers (minutes and project proposals) of the Conference on Jewish Relations reflect Cohen's active role as an advocate of Jewish rights as well as Conference activities. The CJR prepared academic studies on Jewish concerns. Cohen also organized the Jewish Occupational Council to aid the understanding of Jewish employment problems. Also included is material concerning the work of the Jewish Academy of Arts and Sciences, and the Joint Distribution Committee.
Series IV: PUBLISHED WORKS, 1902-1981 consists of reprints, galleys, proofs, book reviews, and journal articles by Cohen. Also included are printed works by authors other than Cohen
Series V: LEONORA COHEN ROSENFIELD PAPERS, 1904-1980 comprises the papers of Leonora Cohen Rosenfield used in the preparation of Portrait of a Philosopher, a biography of her father. The collection contains Rosenfield's manuscripts of the book as well as of related correspondence concerning her research. During her research, she corresponded with many of Morris' personal and professional colleagues, and personal anecdotes of their relationships with Morris can be found. Also included in the correspondence are duplicates of letters from Series I and timeline reconstructions of events from Morris' life. In addition, this series contains personal papers of Rosenfield and her husband Harry Rosenfield.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Subject Headings
Cohen, Morris Raphael, 1880-1947; Logic; Ethics; Law -- Philosophy; Philosophers
INVENTORY
- Series I: Personal and Professional Correspondence, 1899-1946
  - Correspondence, Aaron, Robert Abarbanal, Albert Abbot, Abelson, Paul Abraham, Leo Abraham, Regina Ackerman, Gertrude Ackley, John K. Adamic, Louis Adams, George P. Adams, M Adler, Cyrus Adler, Felix Adler, Helen (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Adler, Phillip Adlerblum, Nina H. Agger, Eugene E. Akzin, Benjamin Albert, A. A. Albert, Ephraim Albrecht, Arthur E. Alexander, Elizabeth A. Alexander, Jerome Alexander, S. Alexander, William Algase, Gertrude Allen, Devere Alonzo, Augustin S. Alsberg, Henry G. Amberg, Ruth Ambrose, Alice American League Against War and Fascism (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Ames, Elizabeth Amos, M. S. Anderson, Manly Angell, L. Gertrude Angell, Robert C. Armstrong, A. C. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Arnold, Thurman Aron, William Aronson, Jacob J. Aronson, Moses J. Arthur, George R. Atkin, Irving Michael Atkins, Charles D. Atwood, B. D. Auchincloss, Priscilla Auel, A. U. Austern, Thomas H. Avery, Janet Woolley Avramoff, Isaac Axley, Ralph E. Ayres, Clarence (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Backer, George Bailey, David A. Baird, J. Kenneth Bakewell, Charles M. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Balamuth, Lewis Baldwin, Roger N. Balet Ball, Allan P. Balogh, Elemer Balsam, James Balz, Albert G. Balz, Dorothy Bancroft, Wilder D. Barbusse, Henri (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Barker Barnes, Albert C. Barnes, Harry Barnwell, Walter Barrows, Sidney Barry, Charles P. Barry, John Bassett, H. K. Bassett, John S. Bates, Henry Bates, John E. Bates, Ralph Battle, George G. Baumgardt, David Baylis, C. A. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Beamus, Lellia M. Beard, Charles A. Beck, Charlton T. Beck, G. F. Beck, Maxmilian Beckhard, B. Beckhard, Matilda Beckman, James Beckman, Thomas Bedey, B. Beer, Thomas Bell, Aaron Bell, J. Carleton Belles, Fowler Benedict, Ruth Benenson, Nellie (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Bengis, Esther Bergmann, Gustav Benitez, Jaime Benjamin, A. C. Benne, Kenneth Bensinger, George C. Berall, Nathane Bergman, Allen K. Bergmann, H. Berkson, P. B. Berkson, Joseph Berliner, Dorothy Berman, M. Bernhard, J. T. Bernstein, B. A. Bernstein, Herman Bernstein, Nahum A. Bernstein, Rosen Bernstein, S. Berson, Ca Bertling Bestson, Joseph Bettinger, B. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Bettman, Alfred Bibring, Emil Biederman, Charles Biffer, G. Bigelow, Harry Bijur, Nathan Billikopf, Jacob Billikopf, Ruth (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Billinger, James Bingham, Alfred M. Bingham, W. V. Biskaver, Joseph Bixler, J. S. Black, Frederick S. Black, George A. Black, Marvin M. Blaglen, Dorothea Blair, Albert Blaisdell, Donald C. Blankner, Fredericka Blaustein, David (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Bliver, Bruce Bloch, Chaim Bloch, Philip Block, S. John Bloom, Bernard G. Bloom, Samuel B. Bloom, Solomon Bloomfield, Meyer and Sylvia Bloomfield, Meyer Bloomgarden, J. Bluhm, Solomon Blumberg, Dorothy Brushnell Blumenberg, Sydney Blumensohn, Jules Blumgart, Leonard (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Board of Education Boardman, W., Jr. Boas, Franz Bogart, John D. Bogert, George C. Bogdanoff, Catherine Bohlen, Francis H. Bohn, William E. Bonaschi, Alberto C. Bookstaber, Philip D. Boorstein, Edward Borgese, G. A. Borodolin, Alexander Boston Book Company Boudin, Louis B. Bousios, Basil N. H. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Bowers, David F. Bowker, R. R. Boyce, Gary C. Boynton, P. H. Brace, Donald Bradby, Philip Brahdy, Leopold Brameld, Theodore Brandeis, Louis B. Brandeis, Susan Brandt, R. B. Brasch, Frederick E. Bréhier, Emile Brennan, G. I. Brenner, Thelma Jaffe Brett, G. S. Brickner, Barnett R. Bridgman, P. W. Brill, Sara C. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Brittain, William M. Brock, Sophia M. Broderick, Bonaventure [T.] Brodsky, Ruth A. Brogan, A. P. Bronson, A. Bronston, Jack Brooks, M. E. Brooks, Philip Brooks, Van Wick Brotman, Oscar L, Jr. Brown, Carrole T. Brown, David L. Brown, Francis J. Brown, Harold C. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Brown, Robert Brown, William Adams Brown, Brownson, Carleton L. [Brumberg?], James E. Buchanan, George E. Buchler, Justus Buck, George B. Buckaner, Scott Buckner, Emory Buell, Raymond L. Bunn, Charles [Bunn?], R.R. Bunzel, Joseph H. Burack, Benjamin Burdick, Charles K. Burgess, Edwin H. Burgess, John S. Burgess, R. L. Burke, Kenneth Burkhardt, B. Burlingham, Charles Burstein, Abraham Burstein, Alexander Burstein, Philip Burton, Ernst Burtt, Edwin A. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Busch, Bertram Bush, Wendell T. Bushbardt, A. [?] Bussey, G. C. Butler, Nicholas M. Butterworth, Ruth C. Buttitta, A. J. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Cabot, Dr. Cahn, Edmond N. Caines, Florence Cairns, Dorian Cairns, Grace Cairns, Huntington Calhoun, Robert L. Calkins, Mary W. Cammer, Moses Cammin, Harold I. Campbell, Albert A. Campbell, Edith C. Campbell, Ruth E. Canell, Arnold (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Cantor, U. Caplin, Mortimer Cardozo, Benjamin N. Carman, Harry J. Carolsfeld Carrara, G. Carsner, Eubanks Cartie, H (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Carton, Donald Carus, Elisabeth Case, Mary S. Castell, Alburey Catlin, S.Y. Cauling (?), Henry S. Cerf, Bennett A. Chabot, Jacob M. Chaffee, Edmund B. Chamberlin, Joseph P. Chandler, Albert R. Channing, Eva Chapman, Emmanuel Chasan, Maurice Chasin, Philip Chelio, R. M. Child, C. M. Childs, Richard S. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Chubb, Percival Chugerman, Samuel Clark, Charles E. Clark, Egbert B. Clark, T. T. Clark, William Claytor, W. Graham, Jr. Clererdon, Laura A. Clifford, Joseph [Climenno?], Hyman Coats, R. H. Cockley, William B. Codell, David L. Coffee, J. R. Cohen, Beatrice (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Cohen, Felix (Box 2, Folder 6-9)
  - Correspondence, Cohen, Florence Cohen, Grace Cohen, Levy Cohen, Irving Cohen, Joseph Cohen, Julius Cohen, Lawrence (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Cohen, Leonard Cohen, Lucy (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Cohen, Mary Ryshpan (Box 2, Folder 12-14)
  - Correspondence, Cohen, Mary Ryshpan (Box 3, Folder 1-6)
  - Correspondence, Cohen, Nellie Cohen, Paul (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Cohen, Sam Cohen, Solomon Cohen, Tom (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Cohen, Victor William (Bill) Cohen, Yetta (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Cohn, Alfred E. Cohn, Edwin J. Cohn, Fannia M. Colie, Edward M. Collier, Nina P. Columbia University Commons, John R. Conger, George P. Conway, Joseph A. Cook, C. E. Cook, D. H. Cook, W. W. Coolidge, W. D. Cooper Cooper Cooper, Leon (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Copeland, Royal S. de Coppet, E. J. de Coppet, Pauline Coralnik, A. Corigliano, Joseph Cory, Herbert E. Coss, John J. Coster, Charles Henry Cottam, R. V. Couch, W. T. Cowen(?), Charles A. Cowling, Donald J. Cowley, Malcolm Crane, Robert T. Creighton, J. E. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Croly, Herbert Cronbach, Abraham Crosby, Margaret Cross, Ephraim Cross, Wilbur Crowne, J. V. Cunningham, G. Watts Curti, Merle Cutter, Annah (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Dahlberg, Edward Daley, Charlotte F. Daly, James Damon, Frances Dangler, Edward Davenport, Frederick M. David, Blanche C. David, Maurice Davidson, David Davidson, Isaac Davidson, Israel (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Davidson, Thomas (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Davidson, William L. Davis, Allan Davis, Mabel Davis, P Dayton, Neil A. Deal, Clyde Dearborn, Ned Deck, Sophia Deiches, Maurice Dekuczynski, Heinz Del Vecchio, Giorgio Deming, W. Edwards (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Dempsey, David Derso Sebeok Desvernine, Pablo Deutsch, Jack G. Deutsch, Josef Deutsch, Monroe Devlin, James J. Dewey, John (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Diamond, Bertram Dicksen, Arthur Dickinson, John Diesendruck, Leo Dillard, Hardy C. Dilman, David L. Dingol, S. Dodd, William E. Dolowitz, Alexander Donahue, Lester B. Donaldson, F. E. Donovan, Richard Dorfman, Norman Douglas, J Douglas, Paul H. Douglas, William O Dover, Lee Dowling, Robert E. Downer, Charles A. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Drabkin, Edward Drachsler, Leo M. Dreier, Mary E. Driesen, Daniel Drodkin, I. E. Dublin, Augusta Dublin, Louis Ducasse, C. J. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Duggan, Stephan Duker, Samuel Dumaine, Jacques Dummer, Ethel Duncan, J Dunham, Barrows Dunn, Gano (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Dunn, Julia Durant, William Dushkin, Alexander Dutton, E. P. Co. Dwan, Ralph H. Dwight, Charles A. S. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Eastman, Fred Eaton, Cyrus S. Ebenstein, William Eckstein, Henry J. Edel, Abraham Edelman, George Edelstein, Harry M. Edlin, William Edman, Irvin Edwards, George W. Ehrlich, Maxwell Ehrman, Sidney M. Eichler, Willi (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Einstein, Albert (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Einstein, Albert, secondary correspondence (Box 4, Folder 10a)
  - Correspondence, Einstein, Elsa Eisner, Jerome Eisner, Mark Elbogen, J Elderton, A. [Elfenbein?], Klein, Dr. Elkin, S. Ellenbogen, Henry D. Elliott, John L. Ely, Mary L. Emerson, Alfred E. Emery, Stephen A. Emmerich, Herbert Endelman, Edward (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Epstein, Charles Epstein, Mrs. Henry Erskine, John Erwin, Reiman G. Ettlinger, H. J. Eukinski, Clarence Evans, Muriel L. Everett, C. Elizabeth Everitt, Walter G. Executive Bureau of City Collections Ewell, Frederick (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Fackenthal, Frank D. Fadiman, Clifton Fagen, Melvin Faine, Hyman Farfel, Moses Farfel, Victor Farrar, John Fechheimer, S. Marcus Fein, Julius Feinberg, B. G. Feinerman, N. Feinsilber, S. Feit, Charles Feldman, Harry Joseph Feldman, Harry Feldman, Herman Feldman, Maurice Fels, Samuel S. Feneco, Lambero Feodin, Reuben Ferkay, Mrs. B. Ferrin, Dana H. Ferron, [Vergilius?] (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Fertig, M. Maldwin Feuer, Lewis Field, E Field, Stanley H. Fields, Harold Finch, George Fineman, H Finerty, John F. Fingerhood, Boris Fingermann, Jacob Fink, David Harold Finke, F. V. Finkel, Asher (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Finkelstein, Louis Finley, John (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Finn, John F. Fireman, Margaret Firestone, John Fishbein, Morris Fisher, Ivy G. Campbell Fisher, Mitchell S. Fisher, Saul H. Fishler, Max Fitch, Frederic B. Fite, Warner (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Fladager, Vernon Flexner, Abraham Fligelman, Frieda Flynn, John T. Folinger, Elliot H. Foll, Charles H. Follett, Mary Forer, Morris L. (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Foster, William E. Fox, G. George Fox, Joseph Fox, Mary Fraenkels and Wechslers Fraenkel, Adolf Fraenkel, Helene Fraenkel, Osmond Frank, Adele Frank, Glenn (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Frank, Jerome (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Frank, Robert T. Frank, Sam (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Frank, Simcha P. Frankel, Lee K. Frankenthaler, Alfred (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Frankfurter, Felix (Box 5, Folder 6-13)
  - Correspondence, Frankfurter, Marion Frankfurter, Paul Frankfurter, Stella Fraser, Mowat G. Freedman, Harold J. Freehof, Solomon B. Freeman, Eugene Frenkel, George P. Freuder, Irene Freund, Paul A. Frey, Alexander Hamilton Frey, Alice H. Friedburg, Herman Friedburg, Martin C. F. Friedel, Esther O. Friedel, Herman (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, Friedenwald, Jonas S. Friedman, Alfred H. Friedman, Israel Friedman, William E. Friedrich, Carl J. Friess, Horace L. Froehlich, Hans Th. Fromenson, A. H. Fronkel, Samuel Fuller, Lon L. Furniss, Edgar S. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Gage, Daniel S. Galgano, Salvatore Galloway, George B. Galston, Clarence G. Gang, Arthur Gardiner, H. N. Garrigues, Ellen E. Garrison, Lloyd K. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Gates, Arnold F. Gaudly, Solomon Gavrin, Joseph Gay, Frederick P. Gayley, Julia Gebhart, Carl Geiger, George R. Gelb, Saadia George Grady Press, Inc. Gerould, James Thayer Gershenfeld, Louis Gettell, Raymond G. Gewirtz, Alan Ghene, Jack A. Gideonse, Harry D. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Gifford, A. R. Gifford, James P. Gignilliat, L. R. Gilbert, Francis Gilbert, William Gilkey, Charles Gill, Bennington P. [Gillman?], Evorts B. Gilmore, E. B. M. Ginn, Edwin Ginsberg, Morris Ginzberg, Louis Gitelson, Leo Glaser, Edward M. Glassberg, James Glaüwing Gleach, Sheldon Gleason, Mary E. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Gobbert, M. R. Goble, George W. Goheen, John Gold, Emanuel M. Gold, Louis Goldberg, David Goldberg, Isaac Goldberg, Jacob Goldberg, Joshua Goldberg, Louis P. Goldberg, Miriam Goldberg, Morris Goldenstein, Raphael Goldenweiser, Alexander Goldenweiser, E. A. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Goldford, A. J. Goldfrank, Esther S. Goldman, Julian Goldman, Max Goldman, Sara Goldmark, Thekla R. R. Goldsmith, Albert R. Goldsmith, Arthur J. Goldsmith, Samuel A. Goldsmith, Sophie L. Goldstein, Harold K. Goldstein, Jonah Goldstein, Kurt Goldwasser, Martin (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Goldwater, S. S. Goodfriend, Grace Goodfriend, S. Goodman, Frank Goodman, Paul Goodman, Teddy Goodrich, Carrington Goodrich, F. L. D. Goodrich, Herbert F. Goodwin, Senator Gordon, David Gottschalk, Louis Gottschalk, Max Gottschall, Morton Goudiss, A. Gourévitch, Boris Gourrich, Paul P. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Grady, William E. Graham, Marcus Granbery, John C. Grant, David E. Grant, John L. Graves, Mortimer Gray, Herman A. Green, Leon Green, Marion Green, May Greenbaum, Edward S. Greenbaum, Samuel (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Greene, Mrs. Chester H. Greene, Jerome D. Greene, Sally Greenfield, William J. Greeter, Diane Gregory, Alyse Gregory, Charles O. Greifer, Julian L. Grentlicher, Paul Gresser, Isabelle Trapp Griffith, Willard Griggs, Edward Howard Griscon, Ludlow Griswold, Edwin Gross, Cornelia Gross, Magnus Gross, Regina Grossel, Frances Grossman, Howard D. (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Grossman, Max (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Grosvenor, Edwin P. Grubruau, A.J. Grunebaum, L. H. Grünstein, William Guillet, Cephas Gumbel, E. J. Gumperz, Julian Gunther, Erma C. Gurewitsch, Maria Gurwitsch, Aron Gutmann, James (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Haas, Robert K. Haber, William Hackett, Francis Hagedorn, Hermann Haggin, R. H. Haider, Carmen Haldane, Lord Hale, Robert Hall, Arnold Bennett (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Hall, Jerome Haller, Henry S. [Halley?], G. P. Hallock, H. G. C. Hall-Quest, Alfred L. Halpern, Edwin Halsey, Frank D. Hammond, William A. Hancock, Winfield S. Hand, Augustus N. Hand, Clemencia Hand, Learned (Box 6, Folder 11)